Jérémie Lagravière

Research Software Developer



Trendelenburgstraße 2, 04289 Leipzig, Germany jeremie.lagraviere@gmail.com • +33 7 57 47 75 99

Top 3% Coder Worldwide • French • 24/09/1982

LinkedIn • Github

Profile

I love working with inspiring people • I am passionate by carrying out advanced research with the most advanced technologies • Lived, studied and worked in 4 different countries • Hope to get better at everything I do • Care about people around me.

Skills

High Performance Computing, Distributed Computing, Python, C, C++, PHP, Java, Data Science, Blockchain programming, Databases

Education

PhD in Computer Science, University of Oslo

2020 | Oslo, Norway

High Performance Computing

Master in Computer Science, University of Tukru ☑ 2014 | Turku, Finland Embedded Computing

MBA - Advanced Information System, University Lyon 3 ☑ 2007 | Lyon, France

IT Architecture and software development

Languages

French

••••

English

10+ years in international environment

Professional Experience: 12+ years

High Performance Computing Engineer, *UFZ* ☑

01/2022 – present | Leipzig, Germany Scientific Computing, C, C++, MPI, OpenMP, Git, Gitlab

Computer Science Engineer, lagraviere.science ☑ 06/2020 – 12/2021 | Lyon, France
Python, C, C++, PyTorch, TensorFlow
Al supervised learning applied to research for breast cancer

Researcher in Computer Science,

Simula Research 🛮

10/2014 - 06/2020 | Oslo, Norway

Data Science, Scientific computing: massively parallel programming, distributed computing

Researcher in Computer Science, Åbo Akademi ☑ 09/2012 – 02/2013 | Åbo, Finland C, SoC, Parallel programming Embedded Programming

Project Manager and Software Engineer,

ATOS, Alten, Norsys ☑
06/2006 – 06/2011 | Lyon & Limoges, France
Managing Engineering Team: up to 8 people
Web development, PHP, Java, SQL, JavaScript

Interests

Hacking competition □ (Top 3% Coder Worldwide on codingame.com),

Guitar (Teacher, Founder of Jam Session Group at Åbo Akademi),

Cinema (French cinema group in Oslo and Turku), **Microcredit humanitarian investor** ☑ (Kiva contributor since 2008)

Publications

A Newcomer In The PGAS World -- UPC++ vs UPC: A Comparative Study $\ \ \Box$

2020

Performance Optimization and Modeling of Fine-Grained Irregular Communication in UPC

2019

On the performance and energy efficiency of the pgas programming model on multicore architectures

2016

Parallel decoder for low density parity check codes: A MPSoC study, /EEE ☑

2013